

My Contacts

Istanbul, Turkey

majihussami@gmail.com

+90 535 681 22 79

(in) NajiAlhusami

NajiAlhusami

Technical Skills

HTML

CSS **Bootstrap** **Tailwind CSS**

JavaScript

Reactjs

Redux

TypeScript

Certificates

JavaScript (The Complete **Guide 2023) 52.5 Hours - UDEMY**

Dec 2022 - Jan 2023

• LINK: Credential URL

React (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) 48.5 Hours - UDEMY

Dec 2021 - Jan 2022

• LINK: Credential URL

Understanding TypeScript 15 Hours - UDEMY

Feb 2023

LINK: **Credential URL**

Languages

Arabic

English Full Professional working

proficiency

Turkish Limited working

proficiency

Soft Skill

- Observation
- **Decision making**
- Communication
- Multi-tasking
- TeamWork

NAJI ALHUSAMI

Frontend Developer

About Me

Web Developer passionate about Front-End Web development. Well-versed in JavaScript and React to build/improve Frontend Web applications, with a strong skill set in Multi-tasking and a background in the networking field. Joining UNDP to deploy their project was one of my best experiences.

Education

Frontend Web Development - Re:Coded

Sep 2022 - Jan 2023

Re: Coded Immersive Bootcamps are highly competitive, with a 5% acceptance rate.

- Completing a 4.5-month immersive design Bootcamp, with 300+ hours of curricula, more than 100 assignments, and project-based learning.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux.
- Working with various design teams to create products across industries.

LINK: **Certificate URL**

Master of Science in Computer Engineering -**Bahçeşehir University**

Feb 2020 - Jul 2022

- Specializations in Data Mining, Network Security, and Computer Vision.
- Strong course in AGILE Methodologies (incl Scrum, Kanban, Extreme Programming (XP), Lean Development and Crystal)

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems Engineering - Eastern Mediterranean University

Oct 2011- Jun 2016

Specializations include Networking, Telecommunication, Signal and Systems, Digital Signal Processing, and Programming.

Professional Experience

Frontend Web Developer - UNDP (SDG AI LAB)

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022 / Remote Volunteer

- Improved the existing software (Digital Technologies Radar development) as measured by SDG AI Lab, by using React and
- Accomplished deployment of the existing software measured by SDG AI Lab, using Gatsby.
- Gained great experience from the UNDP community.

LINKS: UNDP-Volunteers-Link - Certificate URL

IT Help Desk - Syrian Arab Red Crescent (SARC)

Sep 2017 - Oct 2019 /Full Time

Provided help desk services to meet user problems and requests.

IT Networking Engineer - Eastern Mediterranean University

Oct 2016 - May 2017 /Intern

- Installed and configured Routers, Switches and Access Points.
- Troubleshooted hardware and software issues..

Projects

Mad Libs Game - <u>DEMO</u> | <u>CODE</u> Oct 2022 / Full Time

Mad Libs is a phrasal template word game. The project has two articles that allow us to fill in one of them and it will edit the second article.

- I built it with JavaScript and CSS.
- It was my first project as a beginner.

Hangman Game - <u>DEMO</u> | <u>CODE</u> Nov 2022 / Full Time

The project is about the Hangman game.

• I built it with only JavaScript to gain more experience on Javascript.

The Movie Database - <u>DEMO</u> | <u>CODE</u> Nov 2022 / Full Time This project allows us to search for the newest Movies and actors from

Movie Database (TMDB) which is a community-built movie and TV DB.

- I built it with JavaScript and Bootstrap. While doing this project, I aimed to practice DOM manipulation and to work with 3rd party APIs.
- I was the team lead, I gave tasks for each member.

Online Food Order App - <u>DEMO</u> CODE Feb 2023 / Full Time

The project is to order food online through the website.

I built it with Reactis and CSS.

Online Therapist - <u>DEMO | CODE</u> Dec 2022 - Feb 2023 / Full Time

This project allows users to take an appointment with a therapist and take therapy sessions online. Users can search for information on the website.

- I built the website using Reactjs, Redux and Tailwind CSS.
- I took the Redux toolkit part in the project.
 - I led my team for two weeks out of 6.
- I gained the teamwork and communication skills.